James E. McDonald papers, (1904-1997)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Subgroup 2: General Research Files, 1953-1997
  - Series I: Research Files, 1953-1997
    - Hurricanes misc. (Box 41)
    - Hurricanes pre 1950 clippings. (Box 41)
    - Hurricanes influence on Arizona. (Box 41)
    - Hurricane in Arizona. 1970 (Box 41)
    - Hydrology. (Box 41)
    - Hydrostats of other atmospheres. (Box 41)
    - Ice and snow crystals. (Box 41)
    - Ice crystals in clouds. (Box 41)
    - Ice crystals, capacitance. (Box 41)
    - Ice - fall. (Box 41)
    - Ice crystal growth in water. (Box 41)
    - Ice crystals iridescence. (Box 41)
    - Ice physical properties. (Box 41)
    - Ice structure. (Box 41)
    - Indirect sensing inversion methods. (Box 41)
    - Infrared radiation remote sensing. (Box 41)
    - Infrared radiation - misc. (Box 41)
    - Infrared absorption. (Box 41)
    - Infrared absorption by H2O - Kew Chart. (Box 41)
    - Infrared absorption by water vapor - Kew Chart flux data. (Box 41)
    - Infrared radiation - diurnal variability of down coming flux. (Box 41)
    - Infrared exchanges in clouds. (Box 41)
    - Infrared emissivity of water. (Box 41)
    - Infrared radiative flux calculations. (Box 42)
    - Infrared reflectivity of H2O. (Box 42)
    - Instruments and observing techniques pre 1950 clippings. (Box 42)
    - Infrasonics. (Box 42)
    - Cloud physics instrumentation. 1959 (Box 42)
    - Inversions. (Box 42)
    - Irrigation by sprinklers. (Box 42)
    - Irrigation pre 1950 clippings. (Box 42)
    - Jet stream cross section study. (Box 42)
    - Jet stream hydrostatics. (Box 42)
    - Jupiter. (Box 42)
    - Kelvin Effect paper. (Box 42)
    - Kite sounding. (Box 42)
    - Laplacians. (Box 42)
    - Lasers. (Box 42)
    - Laser backscattering x-sections. (Box 42)
    - Latent heat of water. (Box 42)
    - Light sources photometry. (Box 42)
    - Liquid state. (Box 42)
    - Liquid water content of clouds - measurement. (Box 42)
    - Liquid water content, instrument for measurement of. (Box 42)
    - McDonald progress reports. 1953-1954 (Box 42)
    - McDonald progress reports. 1956-1957 (Box 42)
    - McDonald progress report. 1958-1960 (Box 42)
    - MACE. (Box 42)
    - Magnetism. (Box 42)
    - Math. (Box 42)
    - Mars. (Box 42)
    - GH Parm. (Box 42)
    - Measurement instruments. (Box 42)
    - Measurements - aircraft temp. and humidity. (Box 42)
    - Melting of drops. (Box 42)
    - Meteorology and the animal world. (Box 42)
    - Meteorology and the animal world - flight of birds. (Box 42)
    - Meteorology and botany. (Box 42)
    - Meteorology and insects. (Box 42)
    - Meteors (2 folders). (Box 42)
    - Meteors, observations of. (Box 43)
    - Meteors entry of-into atmos. (Box 43)
    - Meteors and rain. (Box 43)
    - Meteorites - early history rep. (Box 43)
    - Micrometeorology of caves. (Box 43)
    - Micrometeorology desert surface. (Box 43)
    - Micrometeorology desert surface temp. (Box 43)
    - Microwave ovens. (Box 43)
    - Mining. (Box 43)
    - Mining - air pollution. (Box 43)
    - Mining - statistics on production. (Box 43)
    - Mirage. (Box 43)
    - Moon, transient lunar phenomena. (Box 43)
    - Moon meteorology. (Box 43)
    - Motion of the atmos. fine scale. (Box 43)
    - Nacreous clouds. (Box 43)
    - Neutrino. (Box 43)
    - Nitrogen oxides. (Box 43)
    - Noctilucent clouds. (Box 43)
    - Noise - attenuation of aircraft noise. (Box 43)
    - Noise and acoustics. (Box 43)
    - Nomenclature. (Box 43)
    - Nonlinear interactions. (Box 43)
    - Nucleation, general references. (Box 43)
    - Nucleation, non-water and sublimation. (Box 43)
    - Numerical methods of integration. (Box 43)
    - Numerical modeling general circulation. (Box 43)
    - Numerical modeling and simulation. (Box 43)
    - Oceanography. (Box 43)
    - Oceanography pre 1950 clippings. (Box 43)
    - Optics. (Box 43)
    - Optics of the atmos. (Box 43)
    - Optical properties of aerosols 1965 NYU Conf. (Box 43)
    - Origin of elements and solar system. (Box 43)
    - Origins of solar system Velikovsky. (Box 43)
    - Orographic precipitation. (Box 44)
    - Oscillations of the atmosphere. (Box 44)
    - Oscillations of drops. (Box 44)
    - Ozone. (Box 44)
    - Ozone and rubber. (Box 44)
    - Photogrammetry of clouds. (Box 44)
    - Photogrammetry of clouds K-17. Summer 1955 (Box 44)
    - Photogrammetry of clouds K-17. Summer 1956 (Box 44)
    - Photographs of mountains near Tucson. (Box 44)
    - Photography raindrop reflection images. (Box 44)
    - Photosynthesis. (Box 44)
    - Physics and sports - Human reaction times. (Box 44)
    - Planetary Met. (Box 44)
    - Planetary atmospheres. (Box 44)
    - Plasma physics magneto hydrodynamics. (Box 44)
    - Plow share. (Box 44)
    - Polarized light. (Box 44)
    - Pollen wettability washout. (Box 44)
    - Precipitation radar measurement of. (Box 44)
    - Pseudo adiabatic cooling rate, numerical evaluation of. (Box 44)
    - Radar. (Box 44)
    - Radar - Airborne. (Box 44)
    - Radar - Aircraft control. (Box 44)
    - Radar - backscattering coefficient - large sphere limit. (Box 44)
    - Radar - backscattering x-section of hydromet. (Box 44)
    - Radar - backscattering x-section of balloons. (Box 44)
    - Radar - data on specific sets. (Box 44)
    - Radar equipment. (Box 44)
    - Radars - surveillance and GCA. (Box 44)
    - Radar - target and back-scatter characteristics. (Box 44)
    - Radar - trackers. (Box 44)
    - Radar - weather radars. (Box 44)
    - Radar meteorology central. (Box 44)
    - Radar meteorology clear air angel echoes. (Box 44)
    - Radar meteorology refraction. (Box 44)
    - Radioactivity and the atmosphere. (Box 44)
    - Radiosonde characteristics. (Box 44)
    - Rainbow. (Box 45)
    - Raob radiation-error study. (Box 45)
    - Rainfall statistics. (Box 45)
    - Raingauge net Summer. 1955 (Box 45)
    - Rainshadow effect. (Box 45)
    - Raoult effect. (Box 45)
    - Relativity. (Box 45)
    - Research at IAP. 1957 (Box 45)
    - Rockets and propellants. (Box 45)
    - Scattering of sunlight. (Box 45)
    - Scattering - Rayleigh. (Box 45)
    - Science, general and history. (Box 45)
    - Science and accidents. (Box 45)
    - Science - boondoggling. (Box 45)
    - Science and economics. (Box 45)
    - Scientific negativism. (Box 45)
    - Scientific optimism. (Box 45)
    - Science and polotics. (Box 45)
    - Science, Quacks. (Box 45)
    - Science and polotics U of A Govt. Dept. Program. (Box 45)
    - Science and social responsibility. (Box 45)
    - Science and technological development. (Box 45)
    - Sewage treatment plant odors. (Box 45)
    - Silver iodide. (Box 45)
    - Silver iodide generators. (Box 45)
    - Silver iodide, photolysis. (Box 45)
    - Skin and sunlight sunburn. (Box 45)
    - Skin cancer (2 folders). (Box 45)
    - Smoking - air pollution. (Box 45)
    - Snow pre 1950 clippings (Box 46)
    - Snow machines. (Box 46)
    - Solar Energy Project IAP. (Box 46)
    - Solar energy conservation pre 1950 clippings. (Box 46)
    - Solar radiation data. (Box 46)
    - Solar radiation in the atmosphere. (Box 46)
    - Solubility of air in liquid water. (Box 46)
    - Sonic booms. (Box 46)
    - Sonic boom, citizens league against. (Box 46)
    - Space program. (Box 46)
    - Sprays - droplets in water atomization. (Box 46)
    - Statistics, general. (Box 46)
    - Statistics and cloud seeding. (Box 46)
    - Statistics and tail of curve phenomena. (Box 46)
    - Scattering, microwave by cloud drops. (Box 46)
    - Statistics inadvertent bias. (Box 46)
    - Statistics, randomization. (Box 46)
    - Statistics - variability examples. (Box 46)
    - Stratospheric water vapor. (Box 46)
    - Stratosphere dynamics. (Box 46)
    - Subsun. (Box 46)
    - SST radiation hazards. (Box 46)
    - Surface physics. (Box 46)
    - Terpenes. (Box 46)
    - Thermal structure (or ATM). (Box 46)
    - Thermodynamics. (Box 46)
    - Thermodynamics - adiabatic processes. (Box 46)
    - Thermodynamics of clouds isoyhermal- adiabatic expansion. (Box 46)
    - Thermodynamics of clouds Dufour and Defay reprints. (Box 46)
    - Thermodynamics lapse rate problem. (Box 46)
    - Thermodynamics diagrams H2O and CO2 phase models. (Box 46)
    - Thesis problems - suggestions. (Box 46)
    - Transistors. (Box 46)
    - Transport of water vapor. (Box 46)
    - Transport, mesoscale. (Box 46)
    - Tropopause. (Box 46)
    - Tropopause data (not in folder). (Box 46)
    - Tropopause heights study - Arizona. (Box 46)
    - Turbidity factor and diffuse rod. (Box 47)
    - Turbulence. (Box 47)
    - Turbulence in severe storms. (Box 47)
    - Turbulence in clouds. (Box 47)
    - Turb. diffusion. (Box 47)
    - Turbulent fluctuations temperature. (Box 47)
    - Twilight phenomena. (Box 47)
    - Twilight bands. (Box 47)
    - Twilight cloud. June 13, 1966 (Box 47)
    - Twilight cloud. May 18, 1966 (Box 47)
    - Twilight clouds ring Flagstaff. (Box 47)
    - Twilight cloud. May 23, 1966 (Box 47)
    - Twilight clouds - misc. (Box 47)
    - Ultraviolet light sources of artificial. (Box 47)
    - Upperatmosphere pre 1950 clippings. (Box 47)
    - Upper atmosphere. (Box 47)
    - Upper atmosphere recombination-attachment. (Box 47)
    - USSR cloud physics research. (Box 47)
    - USSR visit. (Box 47)
    - Vapor pressure saturation over supercooled water. (Box 47)
    - Vapor pressure, saturation and intermolecular attraction. (Box 47)
    - Variability of runoff in mountain watersheds. (Box 47)
    - Venos. (Box 47)
    - Visibility. (Box 47)
    - Visibility and clouds. (Box 47)
    - Visibility - airlight simulation experiment. (Box 47)
    - Visibility of stars during daylight. (Box 47)
    - Visibility reduction due to jet-exhaust carbon particles. (Box 47)
    - Volcanic dust etc. (Box 47)
    - Vortex rings. (Box 47)
    - War - chemical and biological. (Box 47)
    - War and weather by Edward Powers. (Box 47)
    - Washout. (Box 47)
    - Water resources research centers. (Box 47)
    - Waves in the atmosphere. (Box 47)
    - Waves in the atmosphere gravity. (Box 47)
    - Wave clouds. (Box 47)
    - Weather and climate modification - U of Wash Talk. (Box 47)
    - Wea. Mod. Assn. (Box 47)
    - Wilderness society. (Box 47)
    - Wind observations. Summer 1955 (Box 47)
    - Wind and wind damage pre 1950 clippings. (Box 47)
    - Wind velocity measurement. (Box 47)
    - Wind tunnels. (Box 47)
    - Smarting-Moonen prints - good. (Box 47)
    - Wind tunnel, vertical notes. (Box 48)
    - Wind tunnels, vertical design and drawings. (Box 48)
    - Yuma gun. (Box 48)
    - Ray Stanford - Phx. (Box 48)
    - Geo Helm - happy Jack. (Box 48)
    - John Hudson - Tucson. (Box 48)
    - Jack Knowles - Flagstaff. (Box 48)
    - Jerold Levy. (Box 48)
    - Dave McGowen - St. George, Utah. (Box 48)
    - Hugh McSpadden - Mesa. (Box 48)
    - Ronald Thomas. (Box 48)
    - Bill Warren - Prescott. (Box 48)
    - Whitaker - Tucson. (Box 48)
    - Williams - Flagstaff. (Box 48)
    - May 23 items. (Box 48)
    - Other ring cloud reports. (Box 48)
    - Crackpot. (Box 48)
    - Hypotheses, rocket obs. Etc. and UFO obs. (Box 48)
    - Photog list. (Box 48)
    - M.O.P. Correspondence. (Box 48)
    - C.B. Moore Photo. Dec. 6 1965 (Box 48)
    - Religion and cloud. (Box 48)
    - 28th Feb. cloud - special letters, reports, etc, crackpots, odd ones, etc. (Box 48)
    - Official correspondence - MOP. (Box 48)
    - Maps in manila envelope (not in folder). (Box 48)
    - Reactions - misc. (Box 48)
    - Atomic insurance and the AEC. (Box 48)
    - Bodega report. (Box 48)
    - Natural gas and electric power. (Box 48)
    - Radiation damage manuscript. (Box 48)
    - Reactor hazards. (Box 48)
    - Dresden. (Box 48)
    - Weapons systems. (Box 48)
    - Talks, notes, pix, etc. (Box 48)
    - "Nuclear Information" St. Louis. (Box 48)
    - Local fallout. (Box 48)
    - Correspondence Goldwater. (Box 48)
    - U.S. Naval Radiological Def. Lab. (Box 48)
    - M/R Missile data. (Box 48)
    - ICBM sites - press data. (Box 48)
    - Tucson - missile facilities letters to E.D. (Box 48)
    - Udall, S.L. (Box 48)
    - ICBM sites. (Box 48)
    - Civil defense and damage and evacuations and survival. (Box 48)
    - N2 O4 accident. (Box 48)
    - Nuclear attacks on Tucson and Phoenix. (Box 48)
    - Nuclear disarmament. (Box 48)
    - Nuclear bombs effects on weather. (Box 48)
    - Nuclear fusion. (Box 49)
    - Nuclear fusion Lord Rutherford notes. (Box 49)
    - Nuclear - ICBM. (Box 49)
    - Nuclear missiles Tucson and Titans. (Box 49)
    - Adele Smith - Las Vegas. (Box 49)
    - Papers for publication. (Box 49)
    - Publc. Comm AMS. (Box 49)
    - Progressive. (Box 49)
    - Physics teacher. (Box 49)
    - Sci. Am. notes for papers. (Box 49)
    - Symold - STDS. (Box 49)
    - Sigma Xi. (Box 49)
    - TAGU. (Box 49)
    - Tellus. (Box 49)
    - TAGU paper - Correlation Method. (Box 49)
    - Sky and Telescope. (Box 49)
    - Scientific American. (Box 49)
    - Scientific American - 1960+. (Box 49)
    - Subscription. (Box 49)
    - Saturday Evening Post. (Box 49)
    - Science Study Series. (Box 49)
    - Science. (Box 49)
    - Science and Technology. (Box 49)
    - Science general notes. (Box 49)
    - Weather GJRMS. (Box 49)
    - Washington AMS. 1961 (Box 49)
    - Woods Hale AGV meeting notes. (Box 49)
    - Saturday Review. (Box 49)
    - Weather wise. (Box 49)
    - Water resources committee. (Box 49)
    - C of 11 (Committee of Eleven). 1996/97 (Box 49)
    - Committee of Eleven. 1958 (Box 49)
    - Committee of Eleven. 1964-66 (Box 49)
    - C of 11. 1967-68 (Box 49)
    - IAP General Information (Institute of Atmospheric Physics). 1954-55 (Box 49)
    - History of Science Colloq. (Colloquium). (Box 49)
    - Graduate study committee. (Box 49)
    - Library. (Box 49)
    - University matters - JEM (Empty folder). (Box 49)
    - Photographs. (Box 49)
    - Photography. (Box 49)
    - Wm A. Abell (Abell, William). (Box 49)
    - Adams, Geo. O. (Adams, George). (Box 49)
    - Julian Beck - Bremerton. (Box 49)
    - Jeff Cole - ASC (Arizona State College). (Box 49)
    - W. Breed - Flagstaff (Breed, William). (Box 49)
    - Cagle (Cagle, Ben). (Box 49)
    - F.H Carver - Page. (Box 49)
    - Jackson Clark - Tucson. (Box 49)
    - O.M. Clark - Scottsdale. (Box 49)
    - Wm Channon - Camp Verde. (Box 49)
    - Norman Cole - Tucson. (Box 49)
    - Barbara Conley. (Box 49)
    - K.J. Crowther - McNary. (Box 49)
    - Davis - Winslow. (Box 49)
    - I.E. Daniels - Springerville. (Box 49)
    - Roy N. Daniel - Snowflake. (Box 49)
    - Downum - Leupp. (Box 49)
    - Sgt. Arthur A. Francis - ABQ. (Box 49)
    - Ben Gibbons - Chinle. (Box 49)
    - Glauthur(?). (Box 49)
    - H.E. Graham - Flagstaff. (Box 49)
    - Mrs. Gerwitz - Holbrook. (Box 49)
    - J.C. Greenacre. (Box 49)
    - Grand Canyon - Gen.. (Box 49)
    - Bodega Bay. (Box 50)
    - Bodega Bay Technical and Legal. (Box 50)
    - Breeding. (Box 50)
    - Anti-pollution league. (Box 50)
    - USWB studies. (Box 50)
    - Frontier article. (Box 50)
    - General. (Box 50)
    - Windscale. (Box 50)
    - Large manila to Mrs. Pat Paylore from Vice President for Research. Not in folder. (Box 50)
    - Met. Papers - esp Calif. Coast. (Box 50)
    - Ravenswood - statement. (Box 50)
    - San Francisco hearing statements and other items. (Box 50)
    - Ravenswood. (Box 50)
    - Nipomo Dunes. (Box 50)
    - Malibu. (Box 50)
    - San Onofre. (Box 50)
    - San Onofre statement. (Box 50)
    - The Coriolis Effect. (Box 50)
    - Effects on nuclear attacks on Tucson and Phoenix. (Box 50)
    - The Earth's Electricity. (Box 50)
    - Apparent Sun Time for Normal Incidence Solar Radiation Observations (green folder). (Box 50)
    - Manual of Cloud Forms and Codes for States of the Sky (red folder). (Box 50)
    - Publications-list, McDonald (Box 50)
    - Portage Co. Ohio. (Box 50)
    - Institute of Atmospheric Physics: Pilot Reports on Haze Tops and Smoke Plumes (green folder). (Box 50)
    - Rohwer, Mrs. K.S. (Box 51)
    - Clarence Peterson - Bremerton, Wash. (Box 51)
    - T.A. Pape - Alabama. (Box 51)
    - Schley - Flagstaff. (Box 51)
    - Jos. Schadl. (Box 51)
    - Effects of Inhomogeniety and Record Length on Estimates of Correlation and Variability of Precipitation Data. (Box 51)
    - McDonald, J.E., Effect of Momentum-Exchange on the Fall Velocity of an Accreting Hydrometeor. 3/10/62 (Box 51)
    - Evaluation of Weather Modification Field Tests. (Box 51)
    - McDonald, J.E., The Evaporation Precipitation Fallacy. 1/10/62 (Box 51)
    - A Gigantic Horizontal Cloudbow. (Box 51)
    - McDonald J.E., An historical note on an early cloud modification experiment. (Box 51)
    - Homogeneous Nucleation of Supercooled Water Drops. (Box 51)
    - J.E. McDonald, Homogenous nucleation of vapor condensation. 8/7/62 (Box 51)
    - Observations of Freezing Nuclei over the Southwestern U.S., A.R. Kassander, L.L. Sims, J.E. McD. (Box 51)
    - McDonald J.E., Intermolecular Attractions and Saturation Vapor Pressure. 1962 (Box 51)
    - It Rained Everywhere but Here: The Thunderstorm Encirclement Illusion. (Box 51)
    - J.E. McDonald, James Espy and the Beginnings of Cloud Thermodynamics. 2/13/63 (Box 51)
    - McDonald, J.E., Large-sphere Limit of Radar Back-scattering Coefficient. 1962 (Box 51)
    - Maxwellian Interpretation of the Laplacian. (Box 51)
    - McDonald, J.E., Mean Atmos. Residence Time for Particulate Air Pollution. (Box 51)
    - Measurement, Analysis, and Interpretation of Turbulent Temperature Fluctuations. (Box 51)
    - Meridional Allignment of Tropical Cirrus Clouds. (Box 51)
    - Nomenclature of Phase Transition. (Box 51)
    - McDonald, J.E., A note on the aerodynamic effects of internal circulations in small raindrops. (Box 51)
    - McDonald, J.E., A Notes on Anomalouse Adiabiatic Cooling Rates in Clouds. 1/25/62 (Box 51)
    - A Note on the Precision of Estimation of Missing Precipitatin Data. (Box 51)
    - The Physics of Cloud Modification. (Box 51)
    - McDonald, James E., On a Point of Terminology in the Optics of the Rainbow. 1/16/64 (Box 51)
    - McDonald, J.E., Pollen Wettability as a Factor in Washout by Raindrops. 9/23/63 (Box 51)
    - McDonald, On Radar Detection on Non-Spherical Ice Particles. (Box 51)
    - Rain Washout of Partially Wettable Insoluable Particles. (Box 51)
    - McDonald, James E., Raindrop Spatter-Spots. (Box 51)
    - The Rate of Descent of Parachutes from Various Altitudes. (Box 51)
    - McDonald, J.E., On the Ratio of Evaporation to Precipitation. 3/29/60 (Box 51)
    - Remarks on Correlation Methods in Geophysics. (Box 51)
    - Remarks on the Development of the Coriolis Principle. (Box 51)
    - Review of Physics of the Earth's Upper Atmosphere, Hines, et al. (Box 51)
    - Review of Cosmic Rays, Rossi (Box 51)
    - Review of An Introduction to Fluid Mechanics and Heat Transfer, Kay (Box 51)
    - Review of An Introduction to Atmospheric Physics, Fleagle (Box 51)
    - McDonald, J.E., The Saturation Adjustment in Numerical Modelling of Fog. July 19 1963 (Box 51)
    - Saturation Vapor Pressures over Supercooled Water. (Box 51)
    - Scientific Basis of Weather Modification. (Box 51)
    - The Shape of Raindrops. (Box 51)
    - The Shape and Aerodynamics of Large Drops. (Box 51)
    - Should We Know All the Facts About Civil Defense? (Box 51)
    - McDonald, J.E., Some Models of Interest in Meteorological Thermodynamics. (Box 51)
    - J.E. McDonald, Stratospheric Cloud Over Northern Arizona. 3/20/63 (Box 51)
    - McDonald, J.E., Surface Chemistry of Ice Nucleation. 6/27/61 (Box 51)
    - McDonald, A Thermodynamic Relation in the Theory of Homogeneous Nucleation of Supercooled Droplets. 12/18/63 (Box 51)
    - Tucson and the Titans. (Box 51)
    - McDonald, J.E., Use of the Electrostatic Analogy in Studies of Ice Crystal Growth. Zamp= Zeitschift fur Angewan Mathematik un Physik. 4/29/63 (Box 51)
    - McDonald, J.E. 1962, Visibility Reduction Due to Jet-Exhaust Carbon Particles. 1/20/62 (Box 51)
    - McDonald, J.E., Variablity Factors in Mountain-Watershed Hydrometeorology in an Arid Region. (Box 51)
    - J.E. McDonald, What is a Meteorological Engineer? 3/15/60 (Box 51)
    - AMS Publication Committee 1966-69 (Box 51)
    - Dover Publications. (Box 51)
    - Fleagle - Businger review. (Box 51)
    - JGR Style Sheet. (Box 51)
    - Notes on preparation of reports and journal manuscripts. Institute of Atmospheric Physics. (Box 51)
    - Palynology Conf. April 23-27, 1962 (Box 51)
    - R.E. Lapp. (Box 51)
    - Point West. (Box 51)
    - Q.J. Royal Met. Soc. (Meteorological Society). (Box 51)
    - Publ. Comm. AMS, 2nd Series, Cressman. (Box 51)
    - PTA Mansfeld. (Box 51)
    - Refereeing. (Box 51)
    - Reviewing. (Box 51)
    - Reviews of Geophysics. (Box 51)
    - Reporter. (Box 51)
    - Russian X lotion project (?). (Box 51)
    - Russian literature. (Box 51)
    - Physics of Fluids. (Box 51)
    - Pedagogy. (Box 51)
    - Research notes. (Box 51)
    - (Box 52)
      Box 52 contents: pamphlets, handbooks, manuals
    - PSU Cld Dvn (brown binder). (Box 52)
    - Weather Manual for Pilots. (Box 52)
    - The Feasibility of a Global Observation and Analysis Experiment. (Box 52)
    - Gedenkschrift R. Sanger. (Box 52)
    - PA Houghton (lecture notes). (Box 52)
    - Ground Layer Temperature Inversions in an Interior Valley and Canyon. (Box 52)
    - Photochemistry of Polluted Atmospheres. (Box 52)
    - Hydrocarbon Emissions from Automobiles. (Box 52)
    - Seventh Technical Progress Report. (Box 52)
    - Air Pollution Measurements of the National Air Sampling Network. (Box 52)
    - State of California Motor Vehicle Pollution Control Board. (Box 52)
    - Air Pollution…A National Problem. (Box 52)
    - National Goals in Air Pollution Research. (Box 52)
    - California Standards for Ambient Air and Motor Vehicle Exhaust. (Box 52)
    - The Heat Balance of the Earth's Surface. (Box 52)
    - Our Nation and the Sea. (Box 52)
    - Digest of Municipal Air Pollution Ordinances. (Box 52)
    - The Physical State of the Upper Atmosphere. (Box 52)
    - Report Submitted to the Trail Smelter Arbitral Tribunal. (Box 52)
    - Air Quality Criteria for Particulate Matter. (Box 52)
    - Air Quality Criteria for Sulfur Oxides. (Box 52)
    - Air Over Cities. (Box 52)
    - FAA, Instrument Flying Handbook (Box 52)
    - National Conference on Air Pollution - Proceedings. (Box 52)
    - Evaluation Conference, Project Skywater proceedings: Skywater Conference II. (Box 52)
    - Optimization Conference, Project Skywater proceedings: Skywater Conference IV. (Box 52)
    - Pilot Project Review, Project Skywater proceedings: Skywater Conference V. (Box 52)
    - Nucleation Conference, Project Skywater proceedings: Skywater Conference I. (Box 52)
    - Production Conference, Project Skywater proceedings: Skywater Conference III. (Box 52)
    - (Box 53)
      Box 53 contents: microfilm
    - Howell Thesis, Drop Growth. (Box 53)
    - Hangen Thesis MIT, Mil Absorption. 1/21/59 (Box 53)
    - Fritz's Thesis. 1959 (Box 53)
    - Hendrickson, Mass Transfer to Drops. (Box 53)
    - LaNer J Serdin, Mil Theory. (Box 53)
    - Banger WBM. (Box 53)
    - Mason and Ludia, Microphysics of Clouds. (Box 53)
    - Langmen J Blodged, Drop Tragedies. (Box 53)
    - Hocking, PhD Thesis University of London. (Box 53)
    - Blanchard McDonald. (Box 53)
    - Scrase. (Box 53)
    - Pannell and Taylor. (Box 53)
    - Nakaya. (Box 53)
    - Sierra Ancha. (Box 53)
    - Wimbush, M.H., Optical Astronomical Seeing: A Review. 5/5/69 (Box 53)
    - O.F. Barns, Cloud Observing. (Box 53)
    - U. Nakaya, Frost Heaving. (Box 53)
    - Phillips, Iowa. (Box 53)
    - U. Nakaya, Natural Snow. (Box 53)
    - Sherlock. (Box 53)
    - Yuma Test Station. (Box 53)